Christian Bingham.

Christian.Bingham@gmail.com Bingham.is (website) 814.440.5467

about

technical skills

A decade spent designing, launching SaaS tech for the world's largest brands & media platforms. Goldman Sachs alum. Founded & sold Waypoint Media. 70th hire @ AppNexus (now Xandr). Expert at building successful consulting teams.

Advertising Tech (DSP, SSP, DMP, CDP, RTB), Cloud (SaaS, PaaS, IaaS), APIs, scripting, SQL, HTML, CSS, Unix/Linux, PHP, networking concepts, digital privacy & identity

experience

Oracle

Principal Architect, Data Cloud

2018—Present

Data Cloud is an identity platform that helps connect, control, and activate customer data

- Managing architectures & strategic ad initiatives for the world's largest brands & media platforms. My projects deliver valuable business outcomes with minimal tech debt
- Designing behavioral targeting & identity resolution systems capable of unifying online
 & offline signals (i.e website, mobile, in-store, CRM) at enterprise scale
- Published white paper discussing privacy-by-design business strategies & tech. Read more at on Oracle's blog: <u>link.bingham.is/privacy</u>
- Author of open-source command-line tools designed to streamline interactions with Oracle's platform APIs

Upwardly Group

Director of Product and Implementation

2017-2018

Upwardly Group is an Ad Tech consulting collective

- Directed Programmatic business strategy, oversaw Trading & Finance teams
- Managed strategic partnerships, guided new platform relationships through all phases of the execution lifecycle (pitch, scoping, contract, implementation)
- Developed new financial models to better forecast client spend. Deployed in Q4 2017 to track budgets totaling over \$8MM. Using new processes, targets hit within 1.1% of target
- Instituted company-wide best practices, with the goal of optimizing toward portfolio growth and revenue expansion

Waypoint Media

Co-Founder, VP of Client Services

Acquired by FanAl 2013 – 2017

Waypoint was an self-service advertising platform built for monetizing live video. We invented the unblockable in-stream video & banner ad formats.

- Acquired by Fan.ai
- At peak, our tech reached 45M viewers each month. Used by tier-1 streaming companies like Amazon & Twitch.tv to power live advertising needs
- Steered the company toward profitability, managed client go-to-market strategies
- Principal Design Product Manager: Led design & development of UI/UX, client media, Sales collateral

AppNexus

Acquired by AT&T 2010 – 2013

Senior Implementation Consultant, Global Accounts

AppNexus was the world's largest independent digital advertising platform

- 70th employee. Led Publisher Integrations team: 12 direct reports
- Managed large-scale, technical enterprise relationships

 Product Manager for company's first server-to-server APIs, first video exchange product, developed private exchange best-practices, etc.

Relocated to London to scale the company's first international Global Services team

AppNexus London

- Drove 2x headcount growth
- Led hiring, training, continuity across international offices

Goldman Sachs

Financial Analyst, Global Control

2008 - 2010

Regulatory oversight for Asian & domestic security activity, weekly value ~\$2.5BN USD

 Founding member of an open source, internal Knowledgebase accessible to over 25,000 employees worldwide

hobbies

I love to tinker with hardware and hack around software. Past projects:

Open-Source Firewalls – Custom-built, solid-state appliances designed to protect networks against foreign traffic, malware, & suspicious activity

Bootloader Hacking – Installing OSes on unsupported hardware

education

Lehigh University

B.S., Mechanical Engineering